Essential Corp is now preparing to exit ICICI Prudential Life.
According to sources, Protential Corp can sell its entire
almost 22% stake.
What are the details?  Let's take you to Yash.
Yash hi good afternoon tell me brother.
Good afternoon.  So it has been a long innings
that Prudential Corporation and
ICICI Prudential Life Insurance have had
in the Indian life insurance market.  But now
we have come to know from our sources that PIL
Corporation is preparing to sell its entire stake in ICICI PDL
Life Insurance.
Sources
tell us that Pshysical Corporation is preparing to
sell its entire stake of 22% to
potential buyers.  The
value of this entire stake could be approximately ₹1,500 crore as per today's market cap.
And these talks that Credential
Corporation has started to sell its stake,
according to our sources, a very
early talk is going on to
buy a stake in Indian AXA Life Insurance.
So that
a new entry can be made here by selling 22% stake in ICICI PDL Life.
Into a new entity which could be Indian
AXA Life Insurance.  Where
Bharti can
look to buy its entire stake in Principal Corporation.
What is the reason for exiting ICICI PDL Life
Insurance and entering into a new
insurance entity?
According to our sources,
Prudential Corporation wants to have
more control, more ownership and more
involvement in the Indian life insurance
industry so that it can
consolidate its balance sheet globally.  For this
reason, Pdf Corporation is looking at
how it can exit ICICI PDL Life.
Through a block deal or OFS and
enter into a new insurance entity.
Bernstein, a brokerage, has a
very interesting take
on this potential transaction.  Bernstein says
that at one point, the
exit of potential will not have any impact on ICICI Potl's regular day-to-day
business.  But there will be an
overhang of this stake sale which will
remain on ICICI PIL stock.  Ah, overhung
because there will remain an uncertainty as to what price the new
promoter who comes and buys this stake will come at,
what
valuation will he come at, hence there will remain an
uncertainty and according to them
Prudential wants to sell this stake
because the distribution of ICICI Bank has
not supported ICICI Pension Life Insurance much, due to which there has been a
huge loss in the market share of ICICI Prudential Life.
In his presentation, U Rush answered all the questions that were
coming to my mind.
Preparing to exit the potential, 22%
share will be selling goods around ₹18,500.  By
selling this,
Bharti may be preparing to invest money in another insurance company.
And why,
Yash has given a good answer to that too.  There will be an overhang
in ICICI Pro till the time the stake is sold, at what price
will it be sold, who will buy it?  Due to that, there is
stock pressure today, well my mood is also bad
but there will be lingering worry about ICICI PIL
in the stock now, yes thank you so much, leave it.